you said Putin protect us Putin got involved
вы сказали Путин защити нас Путин полез
Yes I have a classmate Sanya Prokhorov
Да у меня Одноклассник Саня Прохоров
went to fight for Donetsk Lugansk and Crimea
пошёл воевать за Донецк Луганск и Крым
died why is he from Rostov Yes, in short, he went to
умер почему он из Ростова Да пошёл
defend you in Crimea And you are all there,
короче защищать вас в Крыму А вы там все
totos mati, that hemorrhoids
тотос мати тот геморой
nek Salam
нек Салам
aleikum Good evening Where are you
алейкум Добрый вечер Ты
from I am from Crimea, from Sevastopol, and
откуда Я с Крыма с Севастополя а сейчас
where is it in
где в
Crimea now Look I am not from Ukraine I
Крыму Смотри Я я не из Украины Это я
wrote the flag I am from Rostov Yes, I am
написал флаг Я сам из Ростова Да я
trolling, in short, the Ukrainians they think that I am
троллю короче украинцев они думают что я
from the European Union
из Евросоюза
like you have it calmly I read
такой как там у вас спокойно бы я читал
that today you have drones going to
что сегодня у вас беспилотники пошли на
Crimea Well, yes, there are some alarms there Well, you should
Крым Ну да да тревоги что-то там ну Вы
hold on They
держитесь бы они короче у нас Ростов
bombed Rostov with their planes too Yes, they
бомбили тоже своими самолётами
bomb many places, but
Да много где бомбят но в Севастополь
they have their eye on Sevastopol I live
что-то они глаз положили пря Я живу
near the beach, that's about ukuv, 10 minutes of walking
около пляжа вот около укув вот 10 минут
And
хобы А
what about on June 23, they hit the beach with
что 23 июня вот ударили по пля торсом
this kind of cassette torso,
этим типа кассетным
yes, we are in Rostov
да мы в Ростове
We just ran there right away
Просто Мы побежали туда сразу с
boys eat in cafes on the tables
пацанами есть в кафешках на столы клали
just earlier Horror I saw in short that there was the
просто ране Ужас Я видел короче что там
daughter of the mayor of Magadan for two hundred who
дочку мэра Магадана за двухсот который
spoke there for his in short yes Everything is
говорил там за сво короче да Всё
cool yes Listen why don't you go to
прикольно да Слушай а что ты не идёшь
defend Crimea
защищать Крым
And I'm asthmatic Well it just happens from birth
А я астматик Ну с рождения просто
I can't understand who I
получается вот я не могу понять я кого
meet from Donetsk Lugansk Crimea no
не встречу из Донецка Луганска Крыма
one fights Why We from Rostov we
никто не воюет Почему Мы из Ростова ны
defend for you And you are all sitting
за вас защищать А вы сидите все
asthmatics No well this is serious I have all the
астматики Не ну это серьёзно у меня все
documents well from birth I was born in Odessa
документы ну с рождения Я в Одессе
so you understand what
родился чтобы ты понимал да какие
documents do you have look you said Putin
документы у тебя смотри вы сказали Путин
protect us Putin Poles Yes I have a
защити нас Путин полес Да у меня
classmate Sanya Prokhorov went to fight
Одноклассник Саня Прохоров пошёл воевать
for Donetsk Lugansk and Crimea died to him Drone
за Донецк Луганск и Крым умер ему Дрон
just flew in Drone mom buried him
прилетел просто Дрон мама его хоронила
without just yes why is he from Rostov yes in
без просто да почему он из Ростова да
short went to defend you in Crimea And you are
пошёл короче защищать вас в Крыму А вы
all there that asthmatic that hemorrhoids some all some Well
там все тот астматик тот геморой нек все
how can all this be who do you
какие-то Ну как все это может ты кого
see in chat roulette nuno  And so many of
видишь в чат-рулетке нуно А так много
my relatives even
кто у меня из из родственников даже из
friends wait you talk about yourself
друзей подожди ты за себя базар веди
like what are you in short you can amatic you
типа что ты короче ты можешь аматик
can dig a trench you can dig near
можешь копать траншее копать можешь под
Kursk you can not You dig so what to
Курском можешь не Копаешь та как
do others need to work or
что делать другим работать же нужно или
should everyone go to war Wait wait
все на войну должны уйти Подожди подожди
stop That is you were shouting Putin see the troops
стоп То есть вы орали Путин види войска
Yes because we are being forced out here and now
Да потому что нас тут вытесняют а теперь
we should Rostov guys for you and you
мы должны ростовские пацаны за вас а вы
will
будете
work no no you are wrong in this case
работать не не ты не прав в этом случае
I will say for myself that I work I am under
я за себя вот скажу что я работаю я при
Pol
Поль
pod Sanya Prokhorov too can work and
подо Саня Прохоров тоже мо работать и
benefit the
приносить пользу
state Well how can you talk
государство Ну как ты можешь говорить
about Sanya Prokhorov that
про Саню прохо что
he is
он
breaking up about
порва про
pogi your
поги сво
dare you want to go to Why should our guys
сме хочешь идти в Почему наши ребята
for your Crimea there I arrived I
должны за ваш Крым там я приехал я в
came to Feodosia in 2016
шестнадцатом году приехал в Феодосию
to rest they said Crimea was annexed
отдохнуть сказали Крым присоединили
arrived on your Crimea is not needed in Sochi in
приехали на не нужен ваш Крым в Сочи в
Anapa is cheaper than in your
Анапе дешевле чем в вашим
Crimea in 2016 I was in
Крыму в шестнадцатом году приехали Я в
Sochi was in Krasnodar
Сочи был в Краснодаре
don't tell me I am from Rostov
был ты мне не рассказывай Я из Ростова
We went to Anapa every year  and Sochi
Мы каждый год ездили в Анапу и Сочи
sixteenth year Let's try Crimea
шестнадцатый год Давай попробуем Крым
New Region Sevastopol go Go with
Новый Регион Севастополь иди Идите вы на
this Crimea expensive Yes, it's not tasty in short
с этим Крымом дорого Да невкусно короче
cockroaches in these in huts in short crawl and
тараканы в этих в хатах короче лазят ещё
you as if we in short yes came like
вы как будто мы короче да приехали типа
and you should not serve us yes And we
и не вы нас должны обслуживать да А мы
owe you something Russians you just
что-то вам должны русские вы просто
know you were and remained Just
знаешь вы как были так и остались Просто
you then Kyiv and now to Moscow do not
вы тогда Киев и тепер в Москву дое не
disgrace yourself Well seriously You Now you
позорь себя Ну серьёзно Ты Сейчас
will say that much Do you hear you you
наговоришь что многого Слышишь ты ты ты
still kept your Ukrainian passport
ещё украинский паспорт сохранил
anyway Yes I No I didn't have it I
по-любому Да я Нет у меня его не было я
made myself a Russian passport after my birth
после сго рождения сделал себе русский
in Crimea in the fourteenth year
паспорт в Крыму в четырнадцатом году
how old are you now 22 22 in the fourteenth year how old
тебе сколько лет Сейчас 22 22 в
were you Well I didn't have a passport yet Well well well you
было Ну не было ещё паспорта Да ну ну ты
were a citizen of Ukraine so I well
же гражданин Украины был так
I had a Ukrainian sstro ID
я ну у меня был украинский сст ро ID
card no certificate good
карта нет свидетельство хорошо
birth certificate yes that is you are a
свидетельство о рождении да то есть ты
citizen of
гражданин
Ukraine I am a citizen of Russia Now
Украины Я гражданин России Сейчас
wait you are not you You are a citizen of two
подожди ты не вы Ты гражданин двух
states and Russia and Ukraine you  you
государств и России и Украины ты хитры
get cunning and there as a disability Yes by
получаешь и там как инвалидность Да по
disability as an amatik and here Yes no no no
инвалидности как аматик и тут
that from the
Да нет нет нет та
mouth And did you refuse Ukrainian
уст А ты отказался от украинского
citizenship or not So I have it
гражданства или нет Так у меня
I don't have it by birthright
его у меня его не есть по праву рождения
site of birth All you were born in Ukraine a
сите рождени Всё ты родился в Украине
citizen of Ukraine Yes you automatically have a
гражданин Украины Да ты автоматически у
Crimean passport everything is already the edge so
меня Крымский паспорт всё уже края так
look from the fact that you take an
нет смотри от того что ты возьмёшь
American passport your
американский паспорт у тебя не пропадёт
Ukrainian and this and Russian citizenship will not disappear you
украинский и этот и русски гражданство
understand citizenship
понимаешь гражданство
passports not No
паспорта не Нет
you no Look not that you leave You
ты нет Смотри не то что оставляешь Ты
must in order to leave Ukrainian
должен чтобы выйти из украинского
citizenship then submit an
гражданства подать тогда ещё порошенку
application to Poroshenko and send that I am such and
заявление да отправить что я такой-то
such like notarized want to
такой-то типа нотариально заверено хочу
leave and you and all of you are waiting for the ZSU to
выйти а вы и все вы ждёте ждуны что там
come there and in short you Then you will
придёт зсу да и короче вы Потом
take out your Ukrainian birth certificates you
достанете свои свидетельства рождения
will wave that we in short are
украинские будете махать что мы короче
not guilty here in short it was us mo like
тут не виноваты короче это нас мо типа
occupied Yes I know you so in Kherson it was so it was that
оккупировали Да я знаю вас так в Херсоне
Listen I drive I drove I
так было было та Слушай я вози Я возил
don't know what you are talking about
не знаю что ты
I am at twenty  in the second year I brought
несёшь я я в двадцать втором году возил
humanitarian aid to Kherson everything in Kherson
гуманитарку в Херсон всё в Херсоне
referendum How in your Crimea they
референдум Как у вас в вашем Крыму
drew 98% for Russia yes we came
нарисовали 98% за Россию да мы приехали
humanitarian aid all the grannies almost
гуманитарку нам все бабушки чуть ли не
kissed us What great guys you are Guys we were
целовали Какие вы Ребята молодцы Мы вас
waiting for you When the ZSU came what is yat that
ждали Когда зсу пришло что такое ят та
granny who gave us on TV
бабка которая у нас на телевидение
in short this is uh comment what great
давало короче это ээ комментарий что
guys volunteers Yes they brought us
Какие молодцы волонтёры Да привезли нам
food Russian volunteers We were
покушать русские волонтёры Мы вас так
waiting for you so much she says the same thing to these
ждали она то же самое говорит этим
Ukrainian volunteers you are such waiters as
украинским волонтёрам вы такие ждуны как
in Kherson understood Well you
и в Херсоне поняли Ну ты
generalize you generalize very much and
обобщает ты обобщает очень сильно причём
why And who in Kherson why the ZSU
Почему А кто в Херсоне почему зсу
came you talk about me If you started
пришло ты говори про меня Если ты начал
saying here No I don't have Krav Horo the
говорить вот Нет у меня нету крав хоро
armed forces of Ukraine will come to
придут вооруженные силы Украины в
Sevastopol What will you do they won't come
Севастополь Что ты будешь делать они не
they won't come Yes in Kherson they also
придут они не придут Да в Херсоне также
said they came in Kursk they also
говорили они пришли в Курске также
said they came because you are all
говорили они пришли потому что вы все
asthmatics sit down nobody wants to raise a laugh
астматики сиди никто не хохочет поднять
Motherland
Родину
and because I need your Crimea if I
а потому что мне ваш Крым нуже если на
attack my Rostov then
мой Ростов нападу тогда буден
Rostov we should not
Ростовская мы не должны Ростовский
die Rostov we should we can bring you
умирать мы должны можем вам привезти там
some buckwheat there help
гречку какие-то помощь там дрона
bring drones there And you this is your war your in short
привезти А вы это ваша война ваши короче
showdowns Yes you have been there for 8 years you have been each
разборки Да вы там 8 лет вы 8 лет друг
other for 8 years In short you couldn't there language
друга Короче вы не могли там язык
Yanukovych go you didn't understand with your
Янукович идите вы на поняли со своим
Crimea Donetsk while you were gone we had no
Крымом Донецком пока вас не было у нас
sanctions everything was fine
санкций не было вс нормально было
now we
сечас нам
need Putin will say from the people If
нуж Путин скажет от народ Если с нас
sanctions are lifted from us we will give up Crimea
снимают санкции отдадим на это Крым
Donetsk Lugansk Kursk region for this That's how I will
Донецк Луганск курскую область Вот так я
only
только за
forget Well you are just telling me now
буду Ну ты просто сейчас говоришь мне
why what is it that mom went to the refrigerator
почему что там мамка к холодильнику
at least you yourself Well don't wait mom And
пошла хоть ты сам Ну не подожди мамка А
what is your mom walking around and you
что у тебя мамка ходит и ты ей
show her quietly No and what Well show it
показываешь тихо Нет а что Ну покажи это
mom So why do I need you so scary
мамка Так зачем мне ты такая-то страшная
with
с
glasses you Oh well insane maybe
очками ты Ай ну невменяемый может
wait And what does she climb to eat at night What a
подожди А что она ночью жрать лезет А
night what does she press at night  climbs at
какая ночь что она ж ночью жать лезет на
night
ночь
Oh she's also asthmatic yes you don't have it I
Ах она тоже астматика да у тебя нет
got it that's you
понял вот это вы
In short I need to record people like you on
Короче я таких как ты надо записывать на
video and post them so that In short all of
видео и выкладывать чтобы Короче их вся
Russia could see them
Россия видела
Well now wait for a summons
Ну теперь жди повесточка
what summons are you What are
какую повесточка
you not going to fight because what am
ты Ты что ты не идёшь воевать ктому что
I saying If Rostov is attacked I
я говорю Вот если на Ростов нападут я
will
буду
defend Why do I need yours In short what are you going to do to me will you
защищать Зачем мне твой короче что ты
send me In short to the
мне сделаешь ты мне пришлёшь короче в
Rostov military registration and enlistment office on a summons you Well then
Ростовский военкомат по весточку ты Ну
you have to fight it That's you have to
так должны воевать ёё Вот вы должны
fight this is your war Crimea Donetsk
воевать это у вас война Крым Донецк
Lugansk we don't have a war in Rostov the
Луганск у нас в Ростове войны нету висит
EU flag is hanging
флаг Евросоюза
here because I'm trolling and I told you I got it I would
у нас потому что я троллю и я тебе
you if I had recorded it In short People like
понял я я тебя если бы записал короче
you need to be recorded and
Вот таких как ты надо записывать и
posted you understand I'm waiting come on I don't
выкладывать понимаешь я жду давай я не
switch so you have to set up a
переключаюсь так что это надо настроить
program that records I'll
программу которая записывает вот я в
set it up next time So that
следующий раз настрою
everything in
Чтобы вс
short pas can
короче па
die In short and you sit there in
помирать короче а вы сидите там в
Sevastopol You still go to the beach on p because I'm
Севастополе Ты ещё на пляж на п потому я
in Rostov there is no war in Rostov that's at  you
в Ростове в Ростове нет войны вот у вас
have Donetsk Crimea Lugansk
есть Донецк Крым Луганск
understood everything let's go let's do it
понял Всё давай пошл на
normally
так нормально
Crimean in short this whole war
Крымский короче эту всю войну
Hello hello where are you from
Здравствуйте здравствуй Вы откуда
I'm from
Я из
St. Petersburg what do you communicate with Armed Forces from
санкт-петербурга чем общаетесь ВС из
Georgia
Грузии
Yes Ukrainian la and we have in chatroulette
Да украинский ла а у нас в чатрулетке
If you look there is no way to
Если Вы посмотрите нет возможности
choose
выбрать
Georgia you cannot choose lists of countries
Грузию вы не можете выбрать списки стран
Georgia Therefore you need to take and enter from
Грузия Поэтому нужно брать и заходить из
some country understood I didn't know this
какой-то страны понял я не знал этот
n I
н я так
understand in
понимаю в
loads in Russian to say Maidan You
грузит по-русски сказать Майдан Вот вы
know this is such a word Maidan how do you
знаете это такое слово Майдан как
feel about this Maidan
относитесь к этому к
for what reason Well against
майдану по какому поводу Ну против
pro-Russian authorities pro-Russian there is pro-
пророссийский власти пророссийский там
Russian authorities Yes also as in
пророссийская власть Да также как в
Ukraine in 2014 Yanukovych refused
Украине в 14м году Янукович отказался от
European integration now we have a similar
евроинтеграции вот у нас сейчас похожая
Theme what do you think will it succeed or what
Тема что как думаете он удастся или что
Yes I think
Да я думаю
everyone will be pro-
уда всех
Russian Tom in 2014 it was more difficult for
прорус Том в 14м году было сложнее
Ukraine Because Russia was
Украине Потому что Россия тогда была
stronger then geopolitical now
более сильно геополитический сейчас
Russia is everything A excuse me should you stream
Россия уже всё А извините вы стримить
or not I stream yes But I generally have
или нет стримлю да А вот я в обще у нас
Georgian stream Yes we have  dedicated to
Стрим грузинский Да у нас посвящённый
uh Revolution and we communicate with different
ээ Революции и мы общаемся с разными
countries how do people perceive our
странами как люди воспринимают наш
Maidan in Georgia And has it just begun
Майдан в Грузии А он он только начался
or has it already taken place? It's been going on for 2
или он уже состоялся 2 дня идёт уже 2
days already. I understand you I have If honestly, there is no
дня идёт Я понял вас у меня Если честно
special opinion on this
нет какого-то особого мнения по этому
matter it would be better to do so and you live there
поводу лучше будет так и делаете вам там
And this is your personal business and how do you feel about the fact that
И это ваше личное дело а как относитесь
Russia seized
к тому что Россия захватила
Crimea seized Crimea to be honest with you To be
Крым захватила Крым честно вам сказать
honest, I don't
Вот честно мне абсолютно всё
care at all Why do you go to chat roulette
равно А зачем вы выходите в чат рулетку
Well, they don't only talk about politics here
Ну тут же не только о политике общаются
correctly Well, I don't know why we communicate economically
правильном Ну я сси зачем экономи
This is my profile topic question
Это оче это моя профильная тема вопрос
How do you feel about that More precisely, not
Как вы относитесь к тому Точнее не так
as you think, what
как вы считаете что
caused such a fall in the ruble against the
повлекло такое падение рубля по
dollar I
доллару я
think well, what kind of well, it fell there by
думаю ну какое такое ну пал там на
15% there is nothing in this
15% ничего в этом
that
нет что
This is a normal fall in a day Yes
Это нормальное падение за день Да
Listen to us In ninety-eight, the
Слушайте у нас В девяносто восьмом году
dollar cost 6 rubles now it costs 115
доллар стоил 6 руб сейчас стоит там 115
In ninety-eight, ninety-
В девяносто восьмом году девяносто
eight, very many  didn't survive
восьмом году очень многие не пережили
True Well who didn't survive You survived
Правда Ну кто не пережил Вы же пережили
everyone survived that is look if we
все пережили то есть смотрите если мы
look Yes here for 15 let's take for 3 years it
смотрим Да тут за 15 возьмём за 3 года
fell even more than 15 True then the question is in the
ещё больше упал чем 15 правда то вопрос
year it fell twice Yes but look you
году он упал два раза Да но смотрите вы
start pouring I asked what
начинаете лить Я спросил что ж стало
caused the fall
причиной падени
uh I suppose a lot of money was
э Я полагаю много денег
printed we need to balance the
напечатали надо сводить
balance Well look I look uh jumps Yes
баланс Ну смотрите я смотрю ээ скачки Да
in the fourteenth year the ruble fell sharply
в четырнадцатом году Резко упал рубль
it wasn't that they printed money sharply it was
это же не резко напечатали деньги это
something geopolitical that happened It
что-то случилось геополитическое Мне
seems to me yes Geopolitics there was politics
кажется да Геополитика там была политика
Yes they weakened the ruble Russia with Russia so and
Да ослабили рубль Росси с росси так а
today this is what happens 2 days or
сегодня вот это получается 2 дня или
how much a week ago they printed
сколько там неделю назад напечатали
a lot of money yes it turns out and the ruble
очень много денег да получается и рубль
ae Well not only this maybe there was a
аэ Ну не только это может был
cumulative effect here in general the ruble is
накопительный эффект вот о вообще рубль
gradually weakening if with with s pya p in
постепенно слабеет если с с пя п в
twenty-second Here it weakened
двадцать втором Вот ослабел вот
so much but it was at 120 there some kind of
настолько но он был у 120 там какой-то
short-term in twenty-second
кратковременно в двадцать втором году
also again because of political events
тоже опять же из-за политических событий
here Well nothing like
вот Ну ничего как бы
digging is correct Well like digging
выкопка правильно Ну как выкопка
look  your key rate is already 22% and
смотрите у вас Ключевая ставка уже 22% и
nabiullina wants to do 23 next
набиулина хочет 23 делать в следующем
month so that is, last month they
месяце так то есть за прошлый месяц два
raised the key rate twice So well and in
раза поднимали ключевую ставку Так ну и
general they have been raising it for six months so that's it yeah yeah yeah Well and
вообще поднимают уже полгода вот так вот
what caused the
дадада Ну а что причинило тому что
key rate to be
ключевую ставку
raised overheated
поднимают перегретая
economy So that is, on the one hand,
Экономика Так то есть с одной стороны у
you printed a lot of money and on the other hand, an
вас напечатали много денег а с другой
overheated economy, something I don't understand, they heated it with
перегретая экономика что-то не Поня
printed money, they printed a lot of money, as I
грели напечатанными деньгами много денег
understand it, they are the
напечатали я так понимаю они идут
basis of defense and everything connected with it This is what
основу оборон и всё что с этим связано
inflates
Вот это раздувает
inflation and raises the rate to
инфляцию и повышает ставку чтобы
fight inflation so And how does the
бороться с инфляцией так А каким
rate increase work out in
образом повышение ставки получается в
Russia, it fights inflation and people throw
России борется с инфляции а люди кидают
money into deposits this is theoretically people
деньги на депозиты это теоретически люди
if I looked because I studied this
если я смотрел потому что я изучал этот
issue too as an economist in Russia
вопрос тоже как экономист в России
the number of deposits has not increased
количество депозитов не увеличилось
significantly for a period you say Well,
существенно период вы говорить Ну вот
over the course of the twenty-fourth
за протяжении двадцать четвёртого
year, we need to raise the statistics I can't tell
года надо поднять статистику я не могу
you anything this is a question ska and also
вам ничего это вопрос ска и также тут
look here The fact is that people bring money
смотри Дело в том что люди несут деньги
to deposits When they have Trust in the
на депозиты Когда у них есть Доверие
authorities and the system  Yes, now, on the contrary,
власти и системе Да сейчас наоборот
regardless of the key rate of trust,
независимо от ключевой ставки доверия
people did not start bringing money into deposits
нет люди на депозиты не стали нести так
and
деньги а
enterprises did not get loans. It became more
предприятия получать кредиты Им стало
difficult for them because loans became simply
сложнее потому что кредиты стали просто
impossible to pay. Yes, they are mega
невозможно оплачивают Да они Мега
expensive. Absolutely right, but I would not
дорогие Совершенно верно но я бы не
rush about trust. If there was a
торопился насчёт доверия Если было бы
collapse of trust, people would take out deposits, it is
обвал доверия люди бы забирали депозиты
logical. The fact is that most
логично ээ Дело в том что большинство
deposits are with a certain term
депозитов они ээ с определённым сроком
without early withdrawal.
без досрочного снятия большинство в
Most of the deposits in Russia. Yes, without
России большинство депозитов Да без
early withdrawal. Well, this is not so.
досрочного снятия Ну это не так
Look at the statistics of 78 e as
Посмотрите статистику 78 э по состоянию
of 2023. I looked. 78% of deposits in the
на 2023 год я смотрел 78% депозитов в
Russian Federation were without early
Российской Федерации были без досрочного
withdrawal because the interest rate is higher there. In
снятия потому что там выше процент в
Russia, there is a law according to which you can
России есть закон по которому ты можешь
withdraw any deposit at any time.
снять любой депозит любое время тебе не
You will not be paid interest. You will
выплатят проценты ты ничего не
earn nothing. You deposit your own at any time.
заработаешь ты депозит сво в любое время
Maybe this is the law. That's right. That's right.
може это закон правильно правильно Вот
Without early withdrawal, you receive. You
ты это Без досрочного снятия получа ты
lose your interest and people don't
теряешь свои процент и люди люди не
want to. I will tell you one thing that the
хотят уже я вам скажу такую вещь что
absolute majority of deposits in Russia are
большинство абсолютно депозитов в России
short-term. If you look and
сес это краткосрочно если Вы посмотрите
open any Russian bank, the
откроете любой Российский банк то самая
highest rate is  there are two or three maximum 4
большая ставка там два-три максимум 4
months Then it falls sharply that's why
месяца Потом она рез падает вот поэтому
fortunately there are practically no US deposits and
благо сши депозитов практически нет а
this is just the point if you look
это просто смысл если смотрите
uh it turns out that we what we see yes that is it turns out that your
ээ получается мы что мы видим да то есть
Key rate rises sharply Yes why
Ключевая ставка Да почему рез Почему
sharply Why sharply Well how if in six months
резко Ну как если за полгода столько раз
it rose so many times is it sharply Well not in
поднималось это резко Да ну не за
six months last year I
полгода она в том году у меня было
think it was 12 now 20 How much 21 yes
по-моему была 12 сейчас 20 Сколько 21 да
or how much is there 22 22 Well 12% in a year is
или сколько там 22 22 Ну 12% за год то
not 12% in a year but twice Well this is
не на 12% за год а в два раза Ну это же
12% this is twice Well and what that is
на 12% это в два раза Ну и что то есть
if it rises from one to two you will
если с одного до два поднимется у вас
also have hysteria this is twice that
тоже будет истерика это в два раза что
this is a twofold increase So what do
это в двукратное увеличение Так а в чём
you see as the problem that this Yes no
вы видите проблему такую что это Да нет
so I don't see a problem for me it's good I'm
так я не вижу пробле для меня хорошо Мне
interested On the contrary, for the economy of the
интересно Наоборот чтобы экономика
Russian Federation to go to hell That
Российской Федерации летела в тартары То
is I don't see a problem in this I'm
есть я не вижу в этом проблему меня
happy with this I'm happy with this I want I'm
устраивает меня это устраивает Я хочу Я
rooting for Nalina to give 23 as soon as possible
болею за то чтобы поскорее налина 23
Before the New Year Yes and maybe more
дала Перед Новым годом Да и возможно ещё
would have managed to finish off 24 before the New Year But
бы успели до Нового года 24 добить Но
that would be cool in general but I think that
это вообще было бы круто но я думаю что
24 will be done in January So what will be the
24 уже сделают в январе Так и что будет
result of this will be the result of
какой результат этого будет результат
deterioration collapse of the economy but you have a KF it
ухудшения схлопывание эконо у вас КФ
turns out you have entered the KFI stage you have
получается вы вошли в этап кфи у вас
both inflation and stagnation of the
одновременно идёт и инфляция стагнация
economy And what is stagnation Yes you are an
экономики А в чём стагнация заключается
economist
в том и заключается Да вы же экономист
you understand yes I am in the fact that look and it turns
вы понимаете да я в том что смотрите и
out that you have yes uh
получается что у вас да
enterprises where all the money is going now
ээ предприятия куда сейчас идут все
Yes here he reports to you what is there
деньги Да вот вам рапортует что там
explain what Talya I understand explain
объясните что Таля я понимаю объясните
what google No look if you
что загуглите Нет смотрите если вам
need to explain the terms you are not right No
нужно объяснять термины вы ж не правда
look you will come let us as an
Нет смотрите Вы приду давайте мы как
economist with an economist we will talk
экономист с экономистом будем говорить
Yes If you said that you are talking about
Да Если вы сказали что Вы говорите по
economics yes you should understand the
экономике да вы должны разбираться в
terms I understand I ask this What is the
терминах я разбираться Я спрашиваю такое
economic downturn so I
В чём экономический спад заключа так я
say again if you do not understand
ещё раз говорю если вы не разбираетесь
so Take Google and Come then
так Возьмите Погугли и Приходите тогда
talk
общаться
Yari so I will say you have production Yes
Яри так вот я скажу у вас производство
now only the
Да сейчас развивается только
military-industrial complex is developing agree
военно-промышленного комплекса согласны
no the rest of the production is collapsing
нет остальное производство схлопывается
everything is not  I agree What kind of production is
всё не согласен Какое производство ва
developing here Bring What kind of
развивается вот Приведите Какое
milk is collapsing collapsing egg collapsing
молочка схлопывается яичные схлопывается
so that they are collapsing here is the production of
чтобы они схлопывается вот производство
butter yes there is not enough butter why is it not
масла да масла не хватать стало почему
enough Or is it collapsing because of what is not
не хватает Или схлопывается из-за чего
enough because it is starting to
не хватает потому что начинает
collapse companies production again
схлопывается компании производству ещё
again look I am telling you it means
раз ещё раз смотрите я вам говорю значит
you had a certain consumption of
у вас было определённое потребление
butter yes something happened that they
масла да что-то случилось что масло
started to produce butter Less means
стали производить Меньше значит
production is collapsing so it is not a fact
производство схлопывается так не факт
maybe demand has decreased maybe this is
может спрос уменьшился может быть такое
no demand is just there because demand is
нет спрос как раз есть потому что спрос
covered by the United Arab Emirates and
покрывают за счёт Арабских Эмиратов и
Turkey or to buy Now no no
Турции ли покупать Сейчас нет нет ещё
again because demand is just yes Balance of
раз потому что спрос как раз да Баланс
supply and demand Yes uh supply has
спроса и предложения Да ээ предложение
fallen sharply it was necessary Uh this
резко упало его нужно было Ээ это
uh to cover from third-party sources yes the United
ээ покрывать из сторонних источников да
Arab Emirates and Turkey this You
Арабские Эмираты и турци это Это вы не
will not in any way not from steam this yes that is
будете никак не от парите это да то есть
Why did Russian producers start to
Почему российские производители стали
produce less butter
меньше масло производить
sharply Well which of them went bankrupt I dont
резко Ну кто из них обанкротился я не
know who I am asking who started to less the
знаю кто Я спрашиваю кто начал меньше
industry is collapsing the
схлопывается отрасль схлопывается
industry is collapsing this is when once it is gone no No
отрасль это когда раз её нету нет Нет
look the industry is collapsing - this is
смотрите схлопывается отрасль - это
when instead of growth Yes it starts to sharply
когда вместо роста Да она начинает резко
decrease  produce it starts she
уменьшать производи она начинает
can you tell me in percentage terms about oil once
ше можете в процентах сказать по маслу
again I see so I see I do not
ещё раз я смотрю так я смотрю я не
have information about the percentage
владею информацией о процентном
ratio of oil but I see that in
соотношении масла но я вижу что масла в
Russia there is a hundred in Russia there is not
России ста в России масла стало не
enough oil agree No I am in the store I have
хватать согласны Нет я в магазине у меня
everything no look you can no longer
всё хватает нет смотри у вас перестаёт
hear something you have or you covered the
слышно у вас что-то или вы закрыли
microphone can not hear it has become very quiet I don't
микрофон слышно не тихо очень
know maybe you
стало не знаю може у вас аргументы
just ran out of arguments no no just In short
просто закончились нет нет просто Короче
you somehow quietly started something you
вы как-то тихо начали что-то у вас
turned off so look oil in Russia
отключилось так смотрите масло в России
yes it has become less and you started importing it
да стало меньше и вы начали его завозить
from Turkey and the United Arab Emirates in a sharp
из Турции и Арабских Эмиратов в резком
order yes we agree yes we have
порядке да согласны у нас да у нас зимой
tomatoes in winter every winter
помидоров становится меньше каждую зиму
look every winter you have not had
смотрите каждую зиму у вас масла не
less oil Well, how
ставало меньше Да ну насколько вы можете
specific can you be I ask you have there
конкретизировать Я вас спрашиваю у вас
become not enough oil in the country I
стало не хватать масла в стране Я жем
say no I have become here it has become there has become
говорю нет у меня стало вот Стало Стало
not enough oil and it has suddenly started
не хватать масла и на него резко начал
because of the fact that demand exceeded
изза из-за того что э спрос превысил
supply so the price of oil has started to rise sharply to
предложение так начала резко расти цена
balance this demand listen
масло сбалансировать этот спрос слушай
No, you know perfectly well you
Нет не Ты же прекрасно знаешь у васс
say abstract things when commenting,
комментировать говоришь абстрактные вещи
I'm not telling you No, these are specific things
не я тебе говорю Нет это конкретные вещи
you now you understand that you have a full one
ты сейчас ты понимаешь что у вас полная
with butter Yes, just like with eggs
с маслом Да так же как с яйцами была у
you had a full one, yes, I do
вас полная да
n't know about the refrigerator, of course you have a full
холоди не знаю яиц конечно у тебя полный
refrigerator, but grandma doesn't have any
холодильник но у бабушки нету какой-то
eggs, she eats, in short, carrots, you understand,
яиц она жрёт короче морковку понимаешь у
of course you have a crisis, who Look, someone
тебя конечно кризис кто Смотри кто-то во
still eats even black caviar during a crisis
время кризиса всё равно ест даже чёрную
and says what a crisis Look,
икру и говорит какой кризис Смотри у
I have black caviar, you have a full
меня чёрная икра у тебя полный
refrigerator, and someone, and your neighbor
холодильник а кто-то а твой сосед
is dying of hunger because he has
умирает с голода потому что ему жрать
nothing to eat, and you're just an ordinary, in short,
нечего а ты просто обычный короче
Russian Let's go So I'm already a little over a
русский Поехали Так я уже что погану
hundred No problems with butter Yes, I left Yes
ста Нет проблем с маслом Да выехал Да
Hello Where are you from Russia Well, I see
Здраствуйте Вы откуда Россия Ну я вижу
what city Moscow I understand I'm from Tiraspol
какой Москва понял Я из Тирасполя
Moldova What do you think, why are Russia and
Молдова Как вы считаете почему Россия и
Ukraine
Украина
fighting, immediately a question like this,
воюет сразу вопросик такой
why Well, at my level Yes At such a small
почему Ну на моём уровне Да На мелком
level, we are fighting because they
таком уровне мы воюем за то что они
betrayed their history there, I think
предали там свою историю там я считаю
it's our
это наша
Earth, at the highest level, I think there is a
Земля на высшем уровне я думаю там
resource there  confrontation with Europe with
ресурс противостояние с Европой с
America Well, I got it,
Америкой Ну поняли
but I don't Understand So why did you Well,
да не Поня Так почему вы ну
confrontation with Europe and America And you
противостояние с Европой и Америкой А вы
attacked Ukraine I can't
напали на Украину не могу
understand Well, because you
понять ну потому что ты поверхностно
think superficially Look, I'm from Moldova I didn't really get into it I'm
думае Смотри я из Молдовы я не сильно
starting to figure it out for the last six months I have
вникал я вот последние полгода Начинаю
friends from Ukraine by the way they
разбираться у меня друзья из Украины
sent me this and I'm
есть мне кстати вот прислали это вот и я
starting to think but I can't understand
начинаю задумываться но я не могу понять
I ask many Russians why if the
Я многих россиян спрашиваю почему если
USA Europe is there Why did you attack
там США Европа Почему вы напали на
Ukraine And you kill mostly the
Украину причём убиваете в большинстве
eastern population of Ukraine
восточное население Украины
Russian-speaking people Bakhmut for example a
русскоязычных людей бахмута например
lot that is and there are a lot of mercenaries now
много то есть и наёмников сейчас очень
not only that is we I even
много не только так то есть мы Я даже
now think that for the most part We due to the fact that
сейчас думаю что большей частью Мы за
there are weapons and all kinds of
счёт того что и оружие там и всякая
armored vehicles there we are
бронетехника там идёт мы большего с
mostly fighting with Europe even with America
частью воюем с Европой даже с Америкой
there is this with an Don't look it
там вот это вот с ан Не смотрите
turns out For example I look at the city of
получается Например я смотрю город
Bakhmut in the Donetsk region there were
бахмут Донецкой области там
Russian-speaking people 70,000 of the population
русскоязычные люди жили 70.000 населения
Russia came and  destroyed this city
Россия пришла и уничтожила этот город
70,000 Russian-speaking people why didn't she
70.000 русскоязычных людей почему она не
go where there to Berlin Yes to some
пошла где там на Берлин Да на какой-то
London Yes why to America to
там Лондон Да почему на Америку что-то
let something in Why to the Russian-speaking people of
пустить Зачем на русскоязычных людей
Donbass in short let in Rake Listen and you
Донбасса короче пустили раке Слушай а ты
look at the direction Well the direction where
посмотри направление Ну направление куда
we are going is exactly the direction
мы идём это вот идёт как раз направление
to Berlin I don't think that We will stop
до Берлина Я не думаю что Мы остановимся
further there I think we will
дальше там Я думаю мы и прибалтику там и
talk a little about the Baltics and Moldova too
с Молдовой тоже немножко поговорим
why does she treat us like that after
почему она так к нам относится после
what we did to her that is to understand gave
того что мы ей сделали то есть понима
you gave us
дали вы дали нам
independence no such thing was
самостоятельность нет такого не было
no Moldova itself declared
нет Молдова сама провозгласила
independence when in what year Well
независимость когда в каком го де Ну
okay and before that it
хорошо а до
means they gave independence SR
этого значит дали самостоятельность СР
entered Well I know how much our some
вошла Ну я знаю насколько наш какой-то
general there used you
генерал там вас использовал
as to transport weapons from that
как чтобы оружие перевозить изго того
on the verge of destruction were destruction by
на грани уничтожения были уничтожение
whom Well look Who is the Romanians there so the Romanians are
кем Ну посмотри Кто там румына так румы
Moldova We are one people so I
это есть Молдова Мы один народ так вот Я
understand Well that's why they absorbed you I
понял Ну вот они вас и поглотили В
mean absorbed we were one people
смысле поглотили мы были одним народом у
we have one language Well right there What are you
нас язык один Ну прямо там Каким вы
one nation were Romanian language came the
одним народом были румынский язык пришли
Soviets made Cyrillic for us
советы кириллицу нам
Moldova ses in general has a difficult
сделали К Молдове сес вообще сложно
attitude That is to say I honestly tell you
отношение То есть я Вас честно гово
state Do you really think you
государство Неужели вы думаете как
can exist as an independent state It was necessary to get
независимое государство можете
under someone
существовать Надо было под кого-то влез
but now you are under the Romanian Lily And before that you
но сейчас вы под румын Лили А до этого
also lay down there I mean we are
также ложились там В смысле мы с румына
one nation with Romania We were in one state of
один народ Мы были в одном государстве
us islands Soviet Soviet Union
нас островия Советский Советский Союз
tore off a piece of Romania like and made
оторвал кусок Румынии типа и сделал
Moldova Transnistria is also Transnistria is
Молдову Приднестровье это тоже
part of Ukrainian
Приднестровье - это часть украинские
territories but they are now in the territory of
территории но они сейчас в территории
Moldova that is Transnistria is
Молдовы то есть Приднестровье это
Ukrainians no no there
украинцы нет нет там
some part of it was once in
э некоторая часть она когда-то была в
Ukraine now it Well under the Soviet
Украине сейчас она Ну При Советском
Union It was already part of Moldova and
Союзе Она уже была в составе Молдовы и
remained part of Moldova It is I flows flows
осталась в составе Молдовы Это я течёт
somehow Well in these same So
течёшь как-то Ну в этих самых Так
wait Transnistria is Moldova
подожди Приднестровье - это это Молдова
Moldova and under Ukraine what does it have to do with the fact that before it
Молдова а при Украина причём что раньше
was the territory of the Ukrainian SSR
это была территория украинское ССР ещё
wait a long time ago we just say you
подожди давно только что говорим ты
say that damn you are one nation With runes
говоришь что блин вы один народ С рунами
And why
А почему
transnistrian Because look No in
приднестровские Потому что смотри Нет в
Transnistria there is still a Russian
в Приднестровье стоит ещё Российская
army that's all Russian army will not be
армия вот и всё Российская армии не
that all
будет че у всех
Transnistrian tel right now axis VN
приднестровского tel прям зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg ORV your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show to people at times do not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
we Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
written right now and Popik there in gram
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в гра
okm video tezh va and kos information and
окм видео ще теж ва и кос информация и
we are responsible for you trimati constant
мы повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational links
оперативный звязок
independently in that chi show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write L
пиши L